“Disturb not the god of flames,
the god of lightning, nor the god of ice.
“Doing so shall invoke the wrath of the heavens and the earth,
destroying our world.
“The god of the sea shall emerge in order to avert the destruction.
"Yet such a violent act cannot be prevented...
“...unless a skilled commander rises
to quell the fury of the gods.”
I desire neither the god of flames,
the god of lightning, nor the god of ice.
I seek the god of the sea.
Meticulous research has confirmed the god of flames
to be the phantom Pokémon, Fire.
Furthermore, this Fire is most likely
the very same specimen...
...who resides near Earthia Island
in the Orange Archipelago.
Likewise, Thunder is the god of lightning,
and Freezer the god of ice.
Thunder and Freezer, like Fire,
can only be assumed...
...to be the same specimens who reside
near Earthia Island.
As expected,
they’re all around Earthia Island.
While they are all Pokémon
I would like to obtain,
my true goal lies further beyond.
Three life readings that resemble
the phantom Pokémon detected.
Fire. Freezer. Thunder.
So they’ve appeared.
Which is closest?
Fire, on Flame Island.
Checkmate.
My collection has grown by one.
Fire, one called a god.
The gods Thunder and Freezer
will join my collection next.
But the true trophy for my collection is
the one which has never been seen...
The god who emerges from
the depths of the sea...
Lugia!
Lugia: The Explosive Birth of a Phantom Pokémon
Blue skies, white clouds, and the wide open sea.
This is the Orange Archipelago
in the southern sea.
Satoshi, whose aim is to
become a Pokémon Master...
...is currently traveling from island to island with his friends.
The weather's great today!
Sure is! Right, Togepi?
Why don't we make the most of it and let our Pokémon out for some sun?
Not a bad idea.
We got plenty of time before we reach the nearest island.
Enjoy yourselves!
All right!
Everyone, come on out!
hoeru haneru sora o tobu
Roar, Flop, Fly
torai atakku megaton panchi
Tri-Attack, Megaton Punch
utau nemuru saikokineshisu
Sing, Sleep, Psychokinesis
roketto zutsuki juuman boruto
Rocket Headbutt, 100,000 Volts
katte mo makete mo omatsuri sawagi
It's like a festival whether you win or lose
batoru shiyou ze pokemon batoru
Let's have a battle, a Pokémon Battle!
maketa kuyashisa wa furueru hodo dakedo
The frustration of having lost makes me tremble
nigiri kobushi o hodoite
But I'll loosen my clenched fists,
zubon de ase fuki akushu shiyou
wipe my sweat on my trousers, and shake your hand!
toki no nagare wa fushigi da ne
The flow of time is such a mystery
docchi ga katta ka ne oboeteru
"Do you remember who won?"
ima de wa hora warai nagara hanashi ga dekiru yo
Now, we can talk while laughing together
wasureta ne tte toboketeru
They play dumb, saying "I forgot!"
sonna ore no raibaru tachi
Those are my rivals
So we ended up here...
Earthia Island... The end of the Orange Archipelago’s sea.
It’s an island!
We’re saved!
What a great feeling, meow!
Maybe not, though...
I'm getting the usual...
...awful feeling?
Oh, Ms. Satoshi’s Mom!
Hard at work, I see!
Oh, Professor Okido!
The oddly good weather this year has helped everything grow so nicely!
For sure, for sure!
The weather's really nice today, too!
What was that just now?
I was wondering the same...
Oh! Cherry blossom petals!
Snow?
But it’s summer...
How could it be snowing?
What’s going on here?
What’s wrong?
What do you think is happening?
Something strange.
Strange things are happening in nature.
We humans may not be able to tell when
something’s wrong with nature,
but Pokémon are far more
sensitive to it than we are.
Looks like we’re safe.
If nothing else,
at least luck is on our side.
Are we really safe?
Oh hey, it’s Micchan!
Long time, no see!
Oh, if it isn’t Yocchan!
How many years has it been?
We last saw each other at the branch school
on Mandarin Island, so that’s five years, I think?
But why are you all
dressed like that?
It’s for the festival!
This island is holding
a festival starting today.
So you’ll be the festival shrine maiden,
playing the flute as always?
I’m retired from that.
I’m not a child anymore.
My little sister inherited the role of festival maiden.
Now, where is she?
Don’t call me “little sister”!
And who’s supposed to be the festival maiden?
It’s just my luck I had to be
born as your little sister!
Why are you dressed like that?
Where’s your festival outfit?
I don’t wanna wear that lame thing!
The festival doesn’t start
until evening anyway, right?
You’re always like this...
This is my little sister, Frula.
She’s supposed to be
a shrine maiden.
She’s playing the leading role in the festival.
Times change, I suppose.
So...?
Oh, this is Satoshi.
He’s a Pokémon Trainer.
A Pokémon Trainer?!
According to the legends,
“When the world faces its demise,
the god of the sea will appear,
“and together with a skilled commander,
it shall quell the fury of the gods.”
A commander...
In other words, a trainer!
You are that commander!
You needn’t be so nervous.
This is just a tradition.
You’re a Pokémon Trainer?
Well, whatever.
Gotta follow the tradition.
We welcome you.
Hmm?
Are you his little sister?
As if!
All right. His girlfriend, then?
No need to be shy!
But just the fact that you followed this guy
all the way out here...
You have great taste.
Now, let’s celebrate!
Oh, my!
I know, right?
Really?
Who’s she calling his little sister?
Who’s she calling his girlfriend?!
And who’s she saying has bad taste?!
I wonder, where did
the girl from earlier go?
There she is! I can tell!
Frula...
Frula?
And she made fun of me?
“When the heavens and earth are enraged,
and the world faces its demise,
“the god of the sea shall appear,
“and together with a skilled commander,
it shall quell the fury of the gods.”
Master Satoshi, if you truly are
a skilled commander,
then please prove it to us!
Prove it...?
Oh, I’m Frula.
Yeah, I got that, but... Um...
Um... Don’t get the wrong idea.
This is part of the tradition.
We do it every year.
Don’t sweat it!
Frula!
And it’s not really
that hard to prove.
Gather three treasures from
the three islands in the surrounding waters,
and place them at
the altar on this island.
Then I will play the flute
for the gods...
...and that’s the end of it.
Where are these treasures?
In the shrines on each island.
It’s all right.
You can get to the islands by boat,
and there are stairs
leading up to the shrines.
Okay! Let’s go right now!
There’s no need to rush.
The festival goes on ‘til tomorrow.
You can do it tomorrow morning.
Just relax.
Don’t put off ‘til tomorrow
what you can do today!
Strike while the iron’s hot, you know?
That’s the rule I live by!
Sure it is...
All right, I like that attitude!
First we head for Flame Island!
I’ll get the boat for you!
Thanks! Kasumi, you coming too?
Why? I’m not your little sister,
girlfriend, or your bodyguard!
Pikachu!
Wait, Pikachu!
Whatever others...
...may say...
We are invincible, meow...
That’s right...
That was...
The brat boy!
Pikachu, too!
“Do not disturb the god of flames,
the god of lightning, nor the god of ice.”
How troublesome...
She said bringing back the treasure
wouldn’t be hard...
But it sure is!
Not difficult...
It’ll be too difficult in this storm!
Sis, lend me your boat!
What are you planning to do
in this storm?
People are in danger
because of our stupid traditions.
What’s more, I was the one
who asked him to go!
This is my responsibility.
Oh? What’s going on?
I’m coming, too.
I’m not his sister, or his girlfriend,
but I’m still going!
Why? Oh, I see. You followed him
all this way, after all.
I didn’t “follow” him!
He just happens to go
everywhere I want to go!
Same here!
If one god abandons you...
Another will save you!
Until now, the three powers
have been in perfect balance.
I have taken one.
Now, in order to fill the void...
A specimen that appears to be Thunder
is headed for Flame Island.
The unprecedented natural disasters
happening all around the world...
...have been confirmed to be the result of
an anomaly in the Deep Sea Current.
The Deep Sea Current is a water current
flowing at the bottom of the ocean,
and is said to control the climate,
weather and nature all over the world.
So something has happened
to the Deep Sea Current?
The anomaly appears to have originated
from the outskirts of the Orange Archipelago.
The Orange Archipelago?
That’s where Satoshi and his friends are...
My phone’s ringing.
This is Uchikido,
from the Orange Archipelago.
Oh, Professor Uchikido!
The Pokémon in the Orange Archipelago
are acting strange.
It’s stopped raining!
But what’s with these waves?
The rudder stopped working!
Well, we’re here...
Pikachu! Where are you going?
Wait!
It’s better you stay here,
considering the weather!
You stay here, Captain!
I’m following Pikachu!
Hold on tight!
You’re good!
Boats are like cradles for
the children on Earthea Island!
I grew up in a Water-type Pokémon Gym.
Gentle waves were my lullaby!
Help!
Oh, Captain! You’re all right!
Thank you for coming to help...
Actually, are you the ones
who need help?
Where’s Satoshi?
We’re falling!
We’re flying?!
Perfect landing!
Oh, my...
Incredible!
We’re going up!
Wouldn’t have it any other way!
Because up here is...
Satoshi?
We came to help him, after all.
You’re going, right?
There’s no use struggling, Fire.
Just wait. Soon you’ll have company...
Thunder has invaded Fire’s territory.
Pikachu!
The brat boy!
We’re in luck, meow!
All right!
Pikachu!
We’re gonna get ‘chu!
This is the treasure?
Like Pikachu to a flame, meow!
What’s that?
If you ask us about “this” or “that”...
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world!
I’m good!
No need to answer, Team Rocket!
I’m in a hurry!
And the weather’s weird.
You’re right.
So while the weather’s still stable,
we’ll have you hand over that Pikachu
on the double!
What’s that?!
There he is! Sheesh, why would you
go all the way up here in this weather?
I’m amazed...
You’ve got guts.
He’s always like this.
Now do you get how hard it is for me
to be around this guy all the time?
Yeah, I get it. It’s because
you love him, right?
I do not!
Hey, kids! It’s ten years too soon for you
to be squabbling about love, hate, and romance!
We’re five years too late for it.
You two will never experience
romance anyway, meow.
What was that?!
Come again?!
That’s Thunder!
Pikachu, stop it!
Pikachu!
What’s he doing?
He has no chance of winning
with an attack like that!
He’s not attacking.
He’s trying to talk to it, meow.
“Why are you doing this?
This is Fire’s island,” he’s saying, meow.
I see.
Translate!
“This island’s master is gone.
“With its master gone,
I will be the one to rule this island instead.
“This island belongs to me now,”
it’s saying, meow.
Now absorbing Thunder’s electricity.
A Pokémon’s electric power...
Artificial beauty brought forth by the power of life.
Now if I can just capture
the last one, Freezer,
this one will appear.
My sincerest apologies.
While capturing Thunder,
something else was captured with it.
Something else?
Thunder...
Fire...
That’s...
“Do not disturb the god of flames,
the god of lightning, nor the god of ice.”
You are the first ones
to ever come here uninvited.
What do you think? The god of flames, Fire,
and the god of lightning, Thunder.
The latest additions to my collection...
Hey, you! If you’re gonna catch Pokémon,
then why don’t you put them in Monster Balls?!
This is just putting them on display!
I am not a Pokémon Trainer.
I am a collector.
I need to be able to look at them with my own eyes
for it to be called a collection.
Have a good look at my collection!
But please no touching.
Use proper etiquette.
Freezer is on the move.
There you are, god of ice.
The god of ice, Freezer...
The anomalies with the Deep Sea Current...
...are believed to stem from around
Earthia Island in the Orange Archipelago.
Also, for reasons unknown,
Pokémon from around the world...
...are making their way
towards Earthia Island.
Water-type Pokémon are crossing the ocean,
while Pokémon who are unable to traverse it...
...are gathering on the landmasses
nearest to Earthia Island.
We will now hear from
Professor Okido and Professor Uchikido...
...what their thoughts are
on this phenomenon.
On Earthia Island, there is a legend saying that
the god of flames, the god of lightning,
and the god of ice live nearby.
If we scientifically analyze this...
If the power of something called the god of ice
were to freeze the ocean,
whatever they call the god of fire
would melt the ice,
and that would cause a sea current to form
at the bottom of the ocean.
I see... A current at
the bottom of the ocean, is it?
Furthermore, if the god of lightning’s electricity
were to interact with the stirred sea water,
it would form proteins,
the base of all living things.
I see... So what does this mean?
Well, to put it simply...
The balance between the three gods
allowed the Deep Sea Current to flow steadily,
and from it,
life on this planet sprung forth.
The central point of the Deep Sea Current
could be considered the origin of life,
the place all living things come from.
This irregularity occurred because something has shattered
the delicate balance between the three powers.
I can only assume that the Pokémon are sensing
the imminent destruction of the planet.
It’s possible they’re unable to make a difference
with their strength alone...
But since the Pokémon have such a close relationship
with the nature of this planet,
they are instinctively gathering,
because they feel that they must do something.
So... who are you?
My son is in the Orange Archipelago!
He’s careless and rash...
I have no idea what he’ll do
if he gets carried away!
There’s no limit to how much danger
he’ll put himself in, you know?
I see...
How troublesome...
Frula...
Oh, my! The southern sea
is completely white.
“Do not disturb the god of flames,
the god of lightning, nor the god of ice.
“Those who do shall enrage the heavens and the earth,
and the world shall meet its demise.”
The legend has come to life!
If the world ends, there’ll be
no more Pokémon for us to steal.
What...
...would become of us?
We’d be out of a job, meow!
We gotta do something!
Let’s save Fire and Thunder!
But how?
To melt ice, you need fire.
Lizardon! You help, too!
Fire and electricity don’t work?!
They’re protected by a powerful barrier!
In that case, we’ll help out, too!
Kojirou! Matadogas!
Got it!
Don’t flinch!
Keep it up, meow!
You don’t have to tell me!
Arbok, attack with Poison Needle!
Zenigame! Fushigidane! Go!
Water Gun and 100,000 Volts...
Electricity splits the water, turning it into
hydrogen and oxygen... H2 and O...
Add a Flamethrower to that, and...
Everybody get down!
Losing altitude. Losing altitude.
Preparing emergency landing on Lightning Island.
Incoming!
Oh, my. They’re...
...totally mad.
At times like these... Act innocent!
This sound...!
Life boat! Life boat!
And... there!
Bring the treasures over there.
The treasures?
You mean these?
Flame Island...
Lightning Island...
Two?
You’re missing one.
Missing one? What’s going on?
Stop it!
The god of the sea...
Lugia!
God of the sea?!
Lugia?!
This sound...!
The god of the sea, Lugia...
This is what I seek.
I want that Lugia!
“The god of the sea will appear
to prevent this demise.
“But it is an act of destruction
which cannot be stopped...”
How troublesome...
Is my Satoshi really in
a dangerous place like this?!
He’s hopeless!
We’re the ones in danger!
No. The entire world is in danger.
The Pokémon know that
better than anyone.
They might not be able
to do anything,
but they cannot fathom
doing nothing.
How troublesome...
“...Unless a skilled commander emerges to
quell the fury of the gods.”
A skilled commander?
You got two of the treasures...
This “skilled commander”
will save the world?
Wait, doesn’t that mean...
No way! Satoshi?!
Who else could it be,
all things considered?
Me? Really?!
H-Hang on!
I do want to be a Pokémon Master...
But I can’t save the world...
I know it’s not like you.
But the only one here
who matches the legend is you, Satoshi.
But didn’t you say my task for the festival
wouldn’t be that difficult?
It was supposed to be easy...
I’m sorry I got you involved in this.
No, it wasn’t your fault...
He always gets carried away
and involves himself in these things.
What should I do?
Wait! If the legend has
been true up ‘til now,
then this flute...
You have my thanks.
The sound of that flute comforts me.
But the flute alone cannot
appease the other three.
What do you mean?
When the treasures belonging to the god of flames,
the god of lightning, and the god of ice...
...harmonize with the flute of the sea,
their rage will be quelled.
That task can only be carried out
by a skilled commander.
It must be done by a human.
You mean I’m the representative
of humankind?
You obtained two treasures.
Only the treasure of ice remains.
I have to... go there?
You are closer than anyone
to saving this world.
Me...
Pikachu...
You guys, too?
All of you...
I get carried away so easily...
Kasumi...
Kenji...
Frula...
Satoshi...
I’ll do it! Time to go save the world!
Easier said than done...
The way there is too long...
This’ll get us there! Thanks, everyone!
Satoshi...
Man, he always gets...
...all the cool parts...
We won’t get to show our stuff
today either, meow.
We will get to show our stuff!
Is this it?
What’s that?
If you ask us about “this” or “that”...
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world!
To protect the world from devastation.
To preserve world peace.
Championing the evils
of truth and love.
We’re the lovely, charming villains.
Musashi!
Kojirou!
The Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy!
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us!
Just kidding, meow!
Team Rocket...
Why?
When the world’s in danger,
we’re all in danger!
When the world’s on
the brink of destruction,
“Evil” and “Justice” cease to matter!
We have but one goal!
World peace!
A world of thieves,
where we can have fun stealing!
Don’t be stupid!
Our goal is Ice Island, meow!
Yeah!
Kojirou! Nyarth!
Roger!
Yahoo!
There it is!
We don’t have time to
stare in awe, meow!
We got the treasure,
so let’s get outta here, meow!
Oh, yeah.
You’re right!
That way, meow!
Do you have the treasure?
Of course!
Get on!
Pikachu!
Wait for us!
Hold on tight!
Could it be that we’re...
...holding them back?
Literally!
In every sense of the term, meow!
So should we stop
holding them back?
To preserve world peace!
Farewell, universe...
A white tomorrow...
...awaits us.
Just kidding, meow!
Team Rocket!
You’re the leading man!
The ocean is beneath us.
But it’s frozen right now.
A sea of ice...
That’s gonna hurt, meow.
It won’t just hurt!
We’re gonna die!
Oh, my!
Amazing!
Are they really all Pokémon?
Indeed. Pokémon who live on
this planet alongside us all.
But why are they doing this?
Because they live together,
they cannot allow these places to be destroyed.
What places?
The others’ worlds.
You have yours. I have mine.
We all have our own,
unique worlds.
Satoshi...
I’ll do it!
Hey!
Magnificent! Truly a befitting addition
to my collection!
It’s over...
Hold this.
I’ll go help Satoshi!
No.
This is your flute.
Your duty.
He’s my burden.
Right?
Satoshi!
Pikachu, leave him to me!
Satoshi, hang in there! Satoshi!
Satoshi!
Satoshi! Hang in there!
The treasure?!
Satoshi!
I have to go...
I have to do this!
Satoshi!
The skilled commander...
This is it, right?
The third treasure...
Frula.
It has recovered all of a sudden!
I repeat, it has recovered all of a sudden!
The Deep Sea Current, which caused all these phenomena,
has returned to normal, and all over the world...
If my remaining a phantom...
...will help preserve happiness on this planet,
then I wish it to be so.
Satoshi! Satoshi!
We finally made it down...
Mom?!
Satoshi! I saw you!
How could you do something so dangerous?!
But Satoshi just saved the world!
So what?!
You’re still just a child.
You can’t be so reckless!
Save the world?
You’d put your life on the line for that?
If you had died...
your world would be gone!
My son would be gone!
The world only exists
because you’re here.
Satoshi... What do you
want to do in this world?
I want to be a Pokémon Master.
In that case... Keep aiming for that goal,
without being reckless.
I will!
All right! I should start researching
this incident right away!
I must go home to Masara Town!
We’re safe...
We’re invincible...
We can still go on, meow...
And... you are?
Things were becoming
quite troublesome.
Thankfully, it all turned out fine.
Yeah... It’s true,
it turned out fine...
Somehow...
This is a really...
...great feeling!
tobimawaru kodomotachi
The children running all around
fushigisou ni nagameru konekotachi mo ga
The kittens watching on curiously
dare mo ga waratte tell me!
They're all smiling. Tell me!
Can you feel it or you can't?
Can you feel it, or can't you?
Don't give up! Turn around!
Close your eyes and tell me how you feel!
Give me something real!
Yes you can do it!
Love warrior
Fight for your love!
chotto shita asobi demo...
The little pranks...
tsumi no nai uso demo...
The white lies...
sonna omoide ni
These memories...
kokoro ga uzuku yo...
...make my heart ache
doko kara ka waite kuru yuuki to kibou de
With untold courage and hope,
oboresou ni natteru kimi o tasuke ni
I'll save you from drowning
dare ni mo shinjite moraenai donna ni
Nobody trusts me,
nagai michi o aruite mayou koto naku susunde mo
no matter the marathons I've run
dare no tame demo nai...
I'm not doing this for anyone else...
jibun to no tatakai o itsu made mo
My battle with myself goes on forevermore
atomodori wa dekinai yo ima kara ja
No looking back... The future starts now
makeru wake ni wa ikanai yo!
I can't lose this fight!
kaeru koto no dekinai unmei
Your fate can never be changed,
dakishimechaou yo
so why don't we embrace it
sabishii sutoorii hitori de sagashite
Seeking out a sad tale alone,
kimi ni chikazuku isshun yume miteru
I dreamed for an instant it brought me to you
doko made tsuzuku no ka wakaranai yozora o
The night sky has no end in sight
futari de habataki maiagaritai
I want us to take wing, fly through it together
hitotsubu no namida ga kawaku koro
When my single tear has dried,
toki ga karamiau
time butts in
kurayami ga sotto me o tsuburi
Darkness sweetly shuts my eyes,
hisoyaka ni mamori tsuzuketeru
my secret protector
kimi ga iru dakara warai koko de namida suru
You are here, so smile, and cry on me
kimi dake no atsui sekai tsuyoku tsukami mamoru
Your passion, your world, I'll hold you tight and protect you
kimi ga iru dakara aishitai hanarenai
You are here, so I'll give you my love, and never leave
kimi dake no atsui sekai tsuyoku dare yori mo
Your passion, your world, I'll hold you tighter than anyone
kaeru koto no dekinai unmei
Your fate can never be changed,
zutto dakishimechaou
so let's embrace it, forever